Guide to the Stanley Dance and Helen Oakley Dance Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Files, research materials, programs and posters
  - Louis Armstrong material (Box 26)
    Program, photo, and discography on index cards.
  - Partial draft of "The Jazz Exiles: American Musicians Abroad" by Bill Moody., 1989-05 (Box 26)
    Includes correspondence from Stanley Dance, with feedback on Moody's early draft.
  - Draft of "The Chiaroscuro Story", a history and discography of Chiaroscuro Records (Box 26)
    Author not specified - possibly Stanley Dance or Helen Oakley Dance.
  - Notes for "Jazz From A to Z: An American Idiom with African Roots" (Box 26)
    Author unknown. Notes likely written by Stanley Dance.
  - "The Best of 1990: A Compilation of Articles Selected by Members of the Jazz Journalists Association" (Box 26)
  - Writings by and about Preston Love (Box 26)
  - Various published articles by Stanley Dance, 1961-1994 (Box 26)
    Includes articles published in The New York Times, Black Music Magazine, Jazz Times, and the Saturday Review.
  - Published copies of "The Jazz Beat" column in the Herald Tribune, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Book Review of "These Jazzmen of our Time" by Stanley Dance (Box 26)
    Typescript of draft written for September Jazz Journal, year not specified.
  - Programs, 1958-1998 (Box 26A)
    Programs from various jazz concerts and festivals. A few of the programs contain handwritten notes on them. Two oversize programs located in Box 55.
  - Dicky Wells scrapbook (Box 27)
  - Date books, address books and financial logs, 1966-1990 (Box 28)
    Includes 8 date books: one from 1966 and the rest dating from 1970-1977. Includes travel details, contact information, and phone numbers.
  - Business Cards (Box 29)
    Arranged alphabetically.
  - Various Song Cards (Box 30)
    Cards include song titles, lyrics, and in most cases, songwriters. Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - "Louis Armstrong" by Hugues Panassié - uncorrected proof copy (Box 30A)
  - Preliminary galleys for "Jazztalk: Basie" by Robert D Rusch (Box 30A)
  - Programs from jazz musicians' funerals (Box 30A)
  - Notes and writings about Louis Armstrong (Box 30A)
  - Copies of Nancy Miller Elliot photographs with correspondence and notes (Box 30A)
  - Concord Jazz: Jeannie & Jimmy Cheatham and the Sweet Baby Blues Band, 1995-1996 (Box 30A)
    Folder includes tracklisting, correspondence, and clippings.
  - Press packets for jazz musicians, 1950-1975 (Box 30A)
  - Dicky Wells hand-written recollections (Box 30A)
  - Ray Charles recollections (Box 30A)
    Appears to be a transcript of a conversation with Ray Charles.
  - Unidentified script for a play (Box 30A)
    Characters include, "Crony", "Cool one", "Moiselle" and "Bannaka" and "Snooky." Takes place at "Cafe Bijou".
  - Various big band parts and signed scores (Box 57)
  - Posters, 1940-1973 (Box 58)
    Ten concert posters for mostly international shows featuring Duke Ellington, Earl Hines and others.
- Clippings
  - Cab Calloway, 1934 (Box 31)
  - Articles by Harold Jovien, 1937-1945 (Box 31)
    Also includes a piece of correspondence from Harold Jovien to Helen Humes.
  - Melody Maker, 1950-1954 (Box 31)
  - Clippings about Billy Eckstine from Melody Maker, 1954 (Box 31)
  - Jazz Hot, circa. 1955 (Box 31)
  - Articles written about Olive Brown, 1963-1964 (Box 31)
    Contains photocopies of several articles written about Olive Brown singing with Buck Clayton's band.
  - Radio Free Jazz Record Reviews, 1977-1978 (Box 31)
  - Radio Free Jazz Record Reviews, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Photocopies of Various Jazz Articles (Box 31)
  - Jazz Times Record and Book Reviews, 1980-1990 (Box 32)
  - Various clippings collected by Stanley Dance, 1990-1993 (Box 32)
    Includes obituaries for jazz musicians and articles from Jazz Forum, the New York Times, and others.
- Photographs
  The Dance Papers contain a sizeable number of photographs. They contain both publicity photos and candid shots.
  Separated Materials
  2-inch stack of damaged snapshots were discarded.
  This series is divided into the following sub-series: Candid shots, Publicity photos, Group photos, Bands, Earl Hines, Duke Ellington, and Photo albums. Note that the candid shots are listed by name, whereas the publicity photos are not itemized.
  During the initial processing of the Dance Papers, each photograph was given a number. These numbers are no longer being used.
  - Candid shots
    - Addison, Bernard, 1937; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Alvin, Danny, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Anderson, Cat, 1950-1968; 7 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Anderson, Ivy, 1936-1937; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Andrews, Ernie, 1957; 1 group photograph. (Box 33)
    - Aqueros, Salvador, 1967; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Armstrong, Louis, 1932-1960; 8 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Ashby, Harold, 1968-1972; 7 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Ashcraft, Squirrel, no date (Box 33)
    - Autrey, Herman, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Babs, Alice, 1968; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Baker, Shorty, 1959-1965; 3 photographs, one photo with Stanley Dance. (Box 33)
    - Barefield, Eddie, 1940-1960; 3 photographs, one in negative. (Box 33)
    - Barksdale, Everett, 1958-1959; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Barton, Eileen, no date; 1 photograph. Autograph on photo, dedicated to Earl Hines. (Box 33)
    - Barnet, Charlie, 1913-1966; 6 photographs. 2 group photos, one including Stanley Dance. (Box 33)
    - Basie, Count, 1940-1982; 46 photographs, 15 of which are photocopies of other candid photographs and concert programs. (Box 33)
    - Bell, Aaron, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Bellson, Louis, 1953-1987; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Benjamin, Joe, 1958; 2 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Benson, George, 1970; 1 color photograph. (Box 33)
    - Berry, Emmett, 1960-1961; 2 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Blake, Eubie, 1969; 4 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Blakey, Art, 1960-1970 (Box 33)
      2 photographs. Includes undated Carnegie Hall concert program
    - Bigard, Barney, 1940-1975; 6 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Bolling, Claude, 1960; 4 photographs. Each photo includes group shots of band performances. (Box 33)
    - Bonnemere, Eddie, 1968; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Boone, Richard, 1968; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Brand, Dollar, 1970; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Brown, Lawrence, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Brown, Louis, 1930; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Brown, Ray, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Broynoghe, Yannick, 1983; 1 photograph: group family shot. (Box 33)
    - Brubeck, Dave, 1967-1970; 4 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Bryant, Marie, 1940; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Buckner, Milt, 1969; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Burroughs, Alvin, No Date (Box 33)
      1 photograph.
    - Callender, Red, 1950-1978; 6 photographs and 7 negatives. (Box 33)
    - Calloway, Cab, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Carney, Harry, 1939-1972; 13 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Carter, Benny, 1956-1987; 8 photographs, one of which in a concert advertisement. (Box 33)
    - Casey, Al, 1935; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Cash, Willie, 1968; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Catlett, Big Sid, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Cheatham, Doc, 1965-1987; 6 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Cheatham, Jimmy, 1984-1987; 2 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Christian, Charlie, 1939; 1 photograph, group shot. (Box 33)
    - Clark, Kenny, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Clayton, Buck, 1950-1987; 7 photographs, 2 with Stanley Dance. (Box 33)
    - Cohn, Sonny, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Cole, Cozy, 1958; 2 photographs. One is with Stanley Dance and the other is autographed by Cozy Cole. (Box 33)
    - Coles, Johnny, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Connors, Chuck, 1972; 2 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Coon, Jackie, 1950; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Copley, Al, 1988; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Crawford, Jimmy, 1958; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Dahlander, Bert, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Davis, Bill, 1978; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Davis, Leonard, 1967; 1 photograph, with Mrs. Bea Davis. (Box 33)
    - Davis, Lockjaw, 1946-1968; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Davis, Richard, 1972; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Deppe, Leo, 1972-1975; 3 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Desmond, Paul, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Dickenson, Vic, 1965; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Dixon, Willie, 1980; 4 color photographs. (Box 33)
    - Donnelly, Ted, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Dorham, Kenny, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Dougherty, Doc, 1957-1960; Two group photographs, one with Stanley Dance. (Box 33)
    - Durham, Eddie, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Edey, Mait, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Eldridge, Roy, 1972-1973; 5 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Ellington (Cole), Maria, 1945 (Box 33)
    - Ellington, Mercer, 1950-1975; 13 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Ellis, Evie, 1934-1965; 54 photographs. Also included is one news clipping, a family Christmas card (a drawing of Evie Ellis' husband), a handwritten note and a poem. One photograph includes handwritten notes to Evie. Several of the photographs are undated but look to be from much earlier than the 1930's. (Box 33)
    - Ellis, Ray, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Ericson, Roy, 1964; 1 photograph with Stanley Dance. (Box 33)
    - Eschete, Ron, 1979; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Estes, "Sleepy" John, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Fields, Herbie, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Finch, Candy, 1967; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Flowers, Pat, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Fox, Ed, 1940; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Freeman, Chico, 1983; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Frye, Don, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Garner, Erroll, 1950-1965; 19 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Gee, Matthew, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 33)
    - Gilmora, Leora, No Date; 2 photographs. (Box 33)
    - Gonsalves, Paul, 1956-1974; 28 photographs. Also includeds a sketch drawing by Paul Gonsalves. (Box 34)
    - Graham, Eddie, 1975; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Grant, Henry (Box 55)
    - Greer, Sonny, 1938-1979; 5 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Grimes, Tiny, 1968-1972; 5 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Guarnieri, Johnny, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hall, Barrie Lee, 1983; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hall, Skid, 1958; 4 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Hampton, Lionel, 1940-1978; 9 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Hanna, Roland, 1987; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hawkins, Coleman, 1958-1964; 4 photographs, one with Stanley Dance. (Box 34)
    - Hawkins, Erskine, 1971; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Heard, J.C., 1922-1950; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Hefti, Neal, 1962; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Henderson, Fletcher, 1928-1947; 8 photographs, one of which is autographed addressed to Fletcher. (Box 34)
    - Henderson, Horace, 1981; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hippler, Al, 1946; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hodges, Johnny, 1932-1968; 31 photographs and 1 negative. (Box 34)
    - Holland, Peanuts, 1943; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Holley, Major, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Holmes, Charles, 1950; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hopkins, Claude, 1974; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Howard, Rosette, 1930; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Humes, Helen, 1950-1979; 3 photographs, one of which is a Christmas card. (Box 34)
    - Humphrey, Bobbi, 1976; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Hurd, Bill, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jackson, Franz, 1944-1966; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Jackson, John, 1942; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jackson, Oliver, 1975-1987; 3 photographs, one with Stanley Dance. (Box 34)
    - Jenkins, Beverly, 1963; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jenkins, Freddy, 1932; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jenkins, Pat, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Johnson, Budd, 1958-1968; 4 photographs, one includes Stanley Dance. (Box 34)
    - Johnson, Harold, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Johnson, Howard, 1968-1972; 3 photographs. Includes two group photos, one with Stanley Dance. (Box 34)
    - Johnson, James P., 1949-1950; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Johnson, Money, 1972; 4 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Elvin, 1968; 2 photographs. Carnegie Hall concert program stapled to the back of one of the photos. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Jimmie, 1947-1950; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Joe, 1958-1970; 4 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Jonah, 1942-1957; 11 photographs, 7 of which include negatives. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Lou, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Rufus, 1968; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Sam, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jones, Slick, 1950; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Jordan, Taft, 1946; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Josie, Marva, 1969-1976; 7 photographs. 2 sheets of photo paper display several smaller photos on them. (Box 34)
    - Kelly, George, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Keyes, Bert, 1958; 4 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Keyes, Lawrence "88", 1965; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - King, B.B., 1960-1975; 3 photographs. One does not show any people but instead a Caesar's Palace (Las Vegas) sign advertising a B.B. King concert. (Box 34)
    - La Rocca, Nick, 1937; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - LaBoy, Margo, 1936; 1 photograph. Signed by Margo LaBoy. (Box 34)
    - Lascelles, Gerald, 1957; 1 photograph attached to family Christmas card. (Box 34)
    - Latifah, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lawrence, Baby, 1970-1978; 2 photographs. One group shot. (Box 34)
    - Laws, Ronnie, 1975; 1 group band photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lawton, Richard, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lenart, Paul, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lim, Harry, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Locke, Eddie, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lousseau, Jacques, 1968; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lowe, Sammy, 1971; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Lucas, Al, 1972; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Machel, Billy, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Mance, Junior, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Marshall, Kaiser, 1940; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Mayus, Lloyd, 1975; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - McCain, Bo, 1950; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - McPartland, Marian, No Date; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - McShann, Jay, 1945-1987; 6 photographs and 2 drawings of Jay McShann. (Box 34)
    - McPhail, Jimmy, 1970; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Metcalf, Louis, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Minor, Piggy, 1942; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Monk, Thelonius, 1967; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Moone, Freddie, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Moore, Archie, No Date; 1 photograph with dedication from Duke Ellington. (Box 34)
    - Morgenstern, Dan, 1966; 2 photographs. One contains information for a birthday party written on the back. (Box 34)
    - Morris, Johnnie, 1970; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Morris, Marlowe, 1950; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Morris, Phatz, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Morrison, Phil, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Mullens, Ed, 1930-1973; 2 photographs. 1 group marching band photo from the early 1930's and one family Christmas card. (Box 34)
    - Mulley Sr., Ed, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Nance, Ray, 1952-1971; 10 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Nanton, 1940; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Newton, Frankie, 1937; 4 photographs. (Box 34)
    - O'Neal, Hank, 1987; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Ory, Kid, 1961; 2 photographs. (Box 34)
    - Otis, Johnny, 1987; 1 photograph of band performing on stage. (Box 34)
    - Owen, Sy, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 34)
    - Page, "Hot Lips", 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Page, Walter, 1942; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Palmier, Remo, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Panassie, Hughes, 1969-1979; 3 photographs. One group photo. (Box 35)
    - Parker, Charlie, 1940-1952; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Perry, Oliver "Doc", No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Phillips, Flip, 1987; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Piccolo, Greg, 1988; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Pimorin, Powell, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Pinkett (Fillis), Loretta (Box 35)
    - Pinkett, Ward (Box 35)
    - Powell, Mel, 1987; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Procope, Russell, 1959-1974; 12 photographs including one with Stanley Dance. (Box 35)
    - Pruitt, Carl, 1957; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Pullen, John, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Ramey, Gene, 1940-1980; 3 photographs, 2 with negatives. (Box 35)
    - Ramirez, Ram, 1945-1973; 4 photographs and 2 negatives. Includes 2 photographs with Stanley Dance. (Box 35)
    - Reid, Irene, 1962; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Richardson, Ben, 1960; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Riley, Ben, 1967; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Riley, Herman, 1985-1987; 4 photographs. Includes Herman Riley's resume. (Box 35)
    - Robbins, Jack, 1948; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Robillard, Duke, 1988; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Robinson, Eli, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Rollini, Adrian, 1930; 2 items. 1 drawing from "The Adrian Rollini Book Project" and a small negative of the same drawing. (Box 35)
    - Ruglin, [Amor], 1941; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Rushing, Jimmy, 1941-1965; 4 photographs, 2 of which are photocopies. (Box 35)
    - Scott, Cecil, 1952; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Sears, Al, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Shaw, Arvell, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Shirley, Jimmy, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Shiraki, Hideo, 1970-1971; 4 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Shorter, Wayne, 1957; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Smith, John, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Slyde, Jimmie, 1972-1973; 5 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Smalls, Cliff, 1973; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Smith, Stuff, 1959; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Smith, Willie, 1965; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Smith, Willie "The Lion", 1956-1972; 8 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Snowden, Elmer, 1965; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Spanier, Muggsy, 1957; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Spivey, Victoria, 1970; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Stephenson, George, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Sterling III, Charles, [1931,1934]; 1 photograph. Date written on back of photograph reads "1931" in pen with a "4" written over the 1 as a correction. (Box 35)
    - Stewart, Rex, 1940-1958; 4 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Stewart, Slam, No Date; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Stitt, Sonny, 1963; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Strayhorn, Billy, 1940-1966; 7 photographs. Also includes a typewritten note about the Duke Ellington Orchestra. (Box 35)
    - Stuart, Ira, 1970; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Tate, Buddy, 1930-1975; 17 photographs with one photograph doubling as a concert avertisement. (Box 35)
    - Tatum, Art, 1951-1953; 5 photographs. One photo doubles as a postcard written to Stanley and Helen Dance. (Box 35)
    - Taylor, Billy, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Taylor, Louis, 1945; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Temple, Johnny, 1957; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Terry, Clark, 1975-1987; 3 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Thomas, Babe, 1945; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Thomas, Joe, 1950; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Mrs. Joe Thomas, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Thomas, Leon, 1968; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Thompson, Billy, 1980; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Thompson, Sir Charles, No Date; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Thompson, Lucky, 1948-1970; 4 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Tizol, Juan, 1960-1980; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Trappier, Arthur, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Turner, Trish, 1968; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Turney, Norris, 1971; 2 photographs. Small color photo is not dated. (Box 35)
    - Urbaniak, Michal, 1989; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Waller, Fats (Box 55)
    - Watkins, Earl, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Wells, Dickie, 1960-1962; 4 photographs and 9 pages of photocopied material. Includes one photo with Stanley Dance. (Box 35)
    - Wells, Gertie (Box 55)
    - White, Sonny, 1958-1969.; 2 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Wilborn, Dave, 1970; 3 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Williams, Cootie, 1963-1971; 12 photographs and 1 negative. (Box 35)
    - Williams, Ernie, 1977; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Williams, Mary Lou, 1945-1972; 5 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Williams, Sandy, 1940-1975; 4 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Wilson, Dick, 1936; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Wilson, Flat Top, 1946; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Woode, Jimmy, 1958; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Woodyard, Sam, 1960-1966; 5 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Wortham, Rozaa, 1969; 3 photographs. one page of photo paper with several photographs, and Rozaa Wortham's resume. One photograph is autographed by Rozaa Wortham. (Box 35)
    - Wright, Gene, 1967; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Young, Hank, 1972; 1 photograph. (Box 35)
    - Young, Snookie, 1940-1957; 5 photographs. (Box 35)
    - Unidentified photos, 4 (Box 35, Box 55)
  - Publicity photos
    - Abrams-Darnell (Box 36)
    - Dell-Hanrahan (Box 37)
    - Harper-McDuff (Box 38)
    - McGregor-Rushing (Box 39)
    - Rutherford-Zwerin (Box 40)
  - Group photos
    In this subseries, "also" denotes an additional photograph. Not all group members are identified.
    - Agueros, Salvador with Benjamin Correa, Joe Morello, Gene Wright, and Dave Brubeck (Box 41)
    - Allen, Harry "Red" with Walter Johnson, Dicky Wells, and Bobby Stark (Box 41)
    - Ammons, Gene with Dodo Marmarose (Box 41)
    - Anthony (Antonini), Ray with Les Brown, Billy Gray, and C Barret [Barnet?] (Box 41)
    - Armstrong, Louis with Hugues Panassié, and Madeleine Gautier. Also, Lawrence Brown, Lionel Hampton, Sidney Catlett, Red Sanders, Sy Oliver, Alton Purnell, Barbara Dane, Trummy Young, Tyree Glenn, Buster Bailey, and Herb Alpert (Box 41)
    - Ashby, Harold (Kenneth), with Russell Riegel (Box 41)
    - Bailey, Mildred with Bing Crosby, Johnny Mercer, Benny Goodman, and Alec Wilder (Box 41)
    - Bank, Danny with Bobby Plater, Jerome Richardson, and Lockjaw Davis (Box 41)
    - Barefield, Eddie with Leonard Cearhim [i.e., Cheatham], Sonny White, Panama Francis, Dee Cheatham, and Benny Maton (Box 41)
    - Barker, Blue Lu with Danny Barker (Box 41)
    - Barker, Danny with Benny Carter, Clark Terry, Floyd Levin, Stanley Dance, and Milt Hinton (Box 41)
    - Barksdale, Everett with Herbie Lovelle and Ship Hall (Box 41)
    - Barnet, Charlie with Tim Whalley (Box 41)
    - Bascomb, Dud with Kelly Martin and Bobby Johnson (Box 41)
    - Bascomb, Paul with Johnny Grimes, Jimmy Mitchelle, Haywood Henry. and Tess Whalley (Box 41)
    - Basie, Count with Don Byas, Buck Clayton, and Buddy Tate. Also, Freddie Green, Frank Wess, Catherine Basie,Hugues Panassié, Helen and Stanley Dance, Gene Ramey, Jo Jones, Jay McShann, Joe Turner, and Nat Pierce (Box 41)
    - Bell, Aaron with Chauncey Westbrook, Roy Burrowes, Sam Woodyard, and Al Lucas (Box 41)
    - Berigan, Bunny with Natalie Natoli, Nick La Rocca, Nat Brown, Leigh Ward, Frankie Warrell, Pete Pumiglib, and Ernie White (Box 41)
    - Bernhardt, Clyde with Spencer Williams, Fats Waller Jr. and Fess Williams (Box 41)
    - Berry, Emmett with Pat Jenkins (Box 41)
    - Brookmeyer, Bob with Frances W. Preston, Manny Albam, and Burt Korall (Box 41)
    - Brown, John with Sonny White, Jonah Jones, Jerome Darr, and Cozy Cole (Box 41)
    - Brubeck, Dave with Herbie Hancock, Frances W. Preston, and Lionel Hampton. Also, Eugene Wright, Joe Morello, and Paul Desmond (Box 41)
    - Bryant, Willie, with Pigmeat Markham (Box 41)
    - Burns, Ralph with Beverly D'Angelo (Box 41)
    - Burrell, Kenny with Illinois Jacquet, and Clark Terry (Box 41)
    - Burton, Gary with Astor Piazzolla (Box 41)
    - Callender, Red with Flip Wilson (Box 41)
    - Calloway, Cab with Evie Ellis and others (Box 41)
    - Carroll, Jeanne with Franz Jackson (Box 41)
    - Candoli, Conte with Frank Rosolino (Box 41)
    - Carter, John Wallace with B. Bradford (Box 41)